[music]
>> Omar, thanks for sitting down with me
here at the owner's meetings out here in
Phoenix. And just kind of wanted to get
your take. I know we talked during
combine, but now at this point, we've
obviously added some quality free
agents. The free agency process is going
on. Just kind of talk about some of the
guys you targeted and why you targeted
them. What makes them Pittsburgh
Steelers? You know, Max, we I always
talk about guys that are Steelers. And
it's always hard to explain it in a few
words of what that means. You know, when
you're around this as long as I've been
around, you just sort of know. You know,
you were a great one. You know, we did
our homework on these guys and they were
all, you [music] know, we filled several
need positions and um
you know, you just sort of know. And we
feel good about these guys. Uh Jamel
Dean and you know, traded for Michael
Pittman and Breion Allen and
they uh they filled some needs and um
you know, they're Steelers.
And I think one of those guys you
mentioned, Michael [music] Pittman, and
making a trade for Michael Pittman, just
kind of talk about what made him the guy
that you guys want to go after. [music]
Sure, you know, I I again, we we did our
our our due diligence on him. We've
known him since he came out uh out of
college and um
you know, the opportunity was there. Uh
I had been in communication with [music]
the uh the Colts, uh their front office,
and it sort of came together pretty
quickly. Uh it made sense for them, made
sense for us, and we're excited to have
them. Also talking about free agents,
Brisker and Dean adding to that
secondary to pair them with Porter,
Ramsey, and hopefully a healthy Deshon
Elliott. Just kind of talk about the
importance of that unit specifically in
today's NFL. Sure, you know, you can't
have enough good players regardless of
position, but believe it or not, Max, uh
the DBs are one of the most injured
positions year after year. You know, we
hope none of our guys ever get hurt, uh
but the reality is, you know, it's a
position where injuries happen and uh
those guys are Steelers and uh
you know, you can't have enough good
players regardless of position. I know,
they can't be as sturdy as offensive
linemen, but you know, those are the
high-value guys. Those If you say so. If
you say so.
>> [laughter]
>> Uh when we talk about the draft process,
um obviously you work with Coach Tomlin
for a long time. How is it working with
Coach McCarthy as you guys kind of get
ready for this draft coming up Yeah,
it's it's it's been great. You know, we
uh I think McCarthy's really embraced
our process. But the cool thing about
it, Max, has been just the new ideas,
you know, and and uh hearing how he's
done it in other places. He's been at
winning organizations and uh successful
organizations that have done it a
certain way and you know, we like how we
do it, but it's there's nothing wrong
with hearing about how other people do
it and just maybe taking some ideas and
putting it in our system and in the way
we do it and that's what we've done.
It's It's It's been fun. I I give a lot
of credit to the coaches, too, you know.
These guys have have been dealing with
moving, uh
having to put a playbook together, you
know, adjusting to to different things
and at the same time, uh you know, we
put a lot on their plate and asked them
to evaluate a lot of football players,
but it's it's been good. So, Omar, with
pro day essentially being wrapped at
this point and now that window before we
actually get to April 23rd in
Pittsburgh, just kind of talk about what
else is there that you guys need to
gather information-wise about these
prospects uh leading up into draft day?
So, the majority of information, with
the exceptions of some medical stuff, uh
we have. So, now it's a matter of
getting our in the meetings for the next
3 weeks and just sorting out our board
and positioning guys where they belong
in our eyes and um just have really good
conversations between the scouts and the
coaches and uh making sure our board is
set. We've got 3 weeks. It's crucial
time and lot lots still has to get done,
but uh in terms of the information we
have, it's just a matter of us uh
sorting through it. Okay. And along with
that information, you have a lot of
picks available at your disposal, 12
picks this year. Can't think of the last
time we've had that many picks in the
draft, especially as many in the top
100. Can you kind of just talk about
what that provides flexibility-wise when
you have that at your disposal?
>> Yeah, we we spoiled Coach McCarthy here
year one of this. I'm I'm hoping he
understands it's probably [laughter] not
realistic we're going to have 12 every
year, but uh you know, we have options.
Um
you know, I'm excited to have it. You
know, there's some good players in this
draft, guys that can help us uh you
know, early and and later in the draft.
And you know, there's there's
opportunities to move up, obviously, if
there's a player we we like. There's,
you know, I'm not opposed to moving back
if if if the opportunity's there and
getting more picks. That's That's how uh
good I feel about the draft. Uh or, you
know, we end up with 12 picks, you know,
happy to have them. And with today's
NFL, you you can't have enough good
players and I'm confident we can get 12
12 good ones. Well, Omar, I appreciate
you sitting down with us here for a
couple minutes. I know you have a lot to
get get done in the next couple of days.
So, thanks for taking the time with us.
>> Thanks, Max. Go Steelers. Go Steelers.